Guide to the Adler & Neilson Iron Work Company Architectural Drawings 1920-1995 PR 415
New-York Historical Society
Adler & Neilson Iron Work Company architectural drawings
1920-1995
New-York Historical Society
Adler & Neilson Iron Work Company
PR 415
56.5 Linear feet in 56 record cartons and one document box
Architectural iron work drawings on trace and waxed trace, from a Queens-based company spanning 70 years. Projects included work on the World Trade Center, LaGuardia and John F. Kennedy Airports, International Design Center (IDC) in Long Island City, Brooklyn Army Terminal, Museum of Modern Art, retail and department stores, hospitals, racetracks, theaters, office buildings, private residences, hotels, and more.
Arrangement
The files in the collection are foldered by project and run in a rough chronological order, with a few exceptions. These files appear to have been given letter designations at some point running in an alphabetical sequence of A-PP (though there are now gaps, especially in the earliest years), but it is not known what specifically that letter designation referred to. The container list presents the boxed content in this letter designation/chronological order. The box numbers assigned by N-YHS do not mirror the alpha sequence because the numbers were assigned to the boxes as found on the shelves as they were prepared for off-site storage.
Biographical / Historical
Queens, NY-based iron work company incorporated March 1920 by Mr. Adler and Henry C. Neilson, and later run by sons David H. Neilson (d. 2005) and Philip B. Neilson (d. 2014).
Alternate addresses for this company are 51 Clark St., Astoria, NY, (circa 1920), 76 Moultrie St., Brooklyn (circa. 1921-1925), and "Jessie Place near Queens Blvd." (after 1926). "Jessie Place" later became 51st Street, hence the firm's ultimate location at 45-48 51st St, Woodside, NY.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The source of the materials is presumed to be the firm itself or one of its principals, but no record of the accession was found when the collection was inventoried in 2020.
Scope and Contents
57 boxes of folded architectural iron work drawings on trace and waxed trace, from a Queens-based company spanning 70 years. Local, tri-state and international projects include terminals at John F. Kennedy Airport (JFK) and LaGuardia Airport (LGA), Brooklyn Army Terminal, Museum of Modern Art, retail and department stores, hospitals, racetracks, theaters, office buildings such as Rockefeller Center and the Federal Reserve Bank, private residences, hotels, and most notably, 4 boxes of World Trade Center drawings circa 1969-1973, Towers "A" and "B" and also buildings 5 and 6, floor by floor, staircases, elevators, etc.
Architectural drawings (visual works); Architectural firms -- New York (State) -- New York.; Architectural ironwork.; Architecture -- New York (State) -- New York.; Commercial buildings -- United States -- Designs and plans.; Hospital buildings -- Designs and plans.; Museum buildings -- Designs and plans.; School buildings -- Designs and plans.; World Trade Center (New York, N.Y.: 1970-2001)
- Files designated with an "A", 1920-1930 (Offsite-box 8)
  Scope and Contents
  Misc. Window Grilles, Main Entrance, Gates, Channel Guards, circa 1920s-1930s; 720 Park Ave., NYC, 1929; Reilly Warehouse, Bergen St., Brooklyn, 1924; John Wanamaker, East 10th St. and Broadway, 1926; Manville Residence, Pleasantville, NY, 1925; Astor Apartments, 40 East 86th St., 1928; Thorn Estate, 37th St. and Sixth Ave., 1921; Lenox Hill Hospital, 76th St. and Lexington Ave., 1930; Gimbel Store, 33rd St., and Broadway, NYC, 1927; Federal Storage Warehouse, Washington, DC, 1925; F.S. Detail at 305 East 61st St., 1924; Biltmore Country Club, Harrison, NY, 1921; Hobart Allport Warehouse, Asheville, NC, 1926; Panhellenic House, East 49th St., NYC, 1927; Broadway Block Building at 51st St., 1929; 510 Park Ave., NYC, 1924; New York University (Bronx location), 1928; Lincoln School of Teachers College, West 123rd St., NYC, 1927
- Files designated with a "B", 1920-1942 (Offsite-box 14)
  "Miscellaneous": Letters, Cast Iron Pickets, Lanterns, Ornamental Brackets, circa 1920s-1930s; Floating Dry Dock in Trinidad, 1942; Coney Island Parachute Jump Tower, 1944; Aviation Facilities in Trinidad, 1941; Canal Zone Coco Solo and Balboa C2 Trinidad, 1941; Firestone Rubber, World's Fair, 1938-39; Swift Exhibit, World's Fair, 1939; Westinghouse Electric Manufacturing, 1938; 71 Park Ave., 1923; Museum of French Art, East 60th St., 1932; Revillon Freras, West 30th St., 1935; Chevrolet, Tarrytown, 1935; Apartment house, East 72nd St., 1927; Stevens Institute, Hoboken, NJ, 1943; Grumman Aircraft, Bethpage, NY, 1942
- Files designated with a "C", 1920-1945, bulk 1920s (Offsite-box 23)
  Miscellaneous Stair and Rails, 1920 -1945 (2 folders); Municipal Building, East Orange, NJ, 1929, (Superb Bronze and Iron, Brooklyn, NY); Union Company of Detroit, 1927 (Superb Bronze and Iron); Hispanic Society, Broadway at 155th St., 1926; 164 East 72nd St., NYC, 1925; Mrs. E.F. Hutton Apartment, Fifth Ave., at 92nd St., 1925; Pennsylvania Railroad Station (Penn Station), 33rd St., NYC, 1926 (2 folders); 720 Park Ave., NYC, 1929; Peter Reilly Warehouse, Bergen St., Brooklyn, 1925; 71 Park Ave., NYC, 1923; Tyler, 17 John St., NYC, 1926; Penhellenic House, East 49th St., NYC, 1926; Central Hanover Bank and Trust, East 72nd St., NYC, 1931; Horatio Street Annex for the New York Edison Company, Philip Lenges Iron Works, Russel St., Brooklyn, NY, 1924; 133 East 64th St., NYC, 1927; Hotel Pierre, East 61 St., 1929 (3 folders)
- Files designated with a "F", 1946-1949 (Offsite-box 4)
  B. Altman, 1946; Electrolyte Storage Facilities, 1946; The Maltine Co., Morris Plains, NJ 1946; National Lead Co., Sayreville, NJ 1947; Raymond Hegeman – Puerto La Cruz, 1947; Westpoint, 1947; Merck and Co., Ramway, NJ, 1947; Brooklyn Union Gas, Maspeth and Varick, Ave., Greenpoint, 1947; Superb Bronze and Iron Co., Terrace Plaza Hotel, Cincinnati, OH, 1947; Naval Militia Base, Whitestone, NY 1947; Sherry-Netherland Hotel, East 59th Street, 1943; Coca Cola, Long Island City, 1947; Daily News Garage, 41st Street, NYC, 1947; Lock Joint Pipe Co., East Orange, NJ, 1947; Zonite, New Brunswick, NJ, 1946; Central Staff Building, NYC Housing Authority, East 42nd St., 1946; Pan-Arcadia Hospital, Tripolis, Greece, 1947; Colby College, Waterville, ME, 1948; Erven Lucas Bols, Inc., Englewood, NJ, 1948; Maracaibo Hospital and Clinic, Venezuela, 1948; Betts Ave. Destructor Plant, Long Island City, 1948; Socony Vacuum, Raritan, NJ, 1948; Crowell Collier Building, 640 Fifth Ave., 1948; National City Bank, 640 Fifth Ave., 1949; Queens College, 1949
- Files designated with a "G", 1948-1953 (Offsite-box 26)
  Daily News Garage, 40th St., NYC, 1948; Oxford Filing and Supply Co., Garden City, NY, 1948; Third Ave. Transit Bus Garage, 218th St., NYC, 1948; Brookhaven Laboratories, Brookhaven, NY, 1949; Bayside Apartments, Bayside, NY, 1949; Pan-Arcadian Hospital, Tripolis, Greece, 1949; Ahepa Hospital, Salonika, Greece, 1949; Culver City Memorial Chapel, Indiana, 1950; Oyster Bay Town Hall, NY; 1950; Greenwood Mills, Inc., Worth St., Thomas St., NYC, 1950; Cooper Hill Apartments, New Rochelle, NY, 1950; Rockaway Sewage Plant, 1951; Jamaica Mines, Belmont Jamaica, 1951 [also in this folder: Empire State Building, Clare Bauer Residence, Ridgewood, NJ; 136 Greenwich Street]; Park Knoll Gardens, Harrison, NY, 1951; Henry Pape, Inc., Woodhaven Blvd., Glendale, NY, 1951; Museum of Modern Art, 53rd St., NYC, 1951; Morris High School, Bronx, NY, 1951; Ganesvoort Destructor Plant, Ganesvoort St., NYC, 1951; McKesson and Robbins, Metropolitan Ave., Queens, NY, 1951; Communication Building "A" U.S. Army, 1951; Union Carbon & Carbide, Niagara Falls, NY, 1951; Atlantic Beach Bridge, 1952; North Atlantic Constructors, NYC, 1952; Ernest Harmon Air Force Base, Metcalfe Hamilton Co., 1952; F.W. Olin Hall, Cornell University Medical College, 69th St., NYC, 1953; Great Neck Trust Co., 1953; Westchester Airport, 1953; Avon Products, Inc., Suffern, NY, 1953; Macy's Parkchester, Bronx, NY, 1953; Roosevelt Field, Long Island, NY, 1953; Millbank Residence, 68th St., NYC, 1953; American Cystoscope, 63rd St., NYC, 1953; St. Thomas Church Choir School, 55th St., NYC, 1953; Montville Generating Station, Montville, CT, 1953; Manufacturers Trust Co., Fifth Ave., NYC, 1953; Metropolitan Life Insurance Co., Madison Ave., NYC, 1953; Gould Student Center, New York University, NYC, 1954
- Files designated with a "H" (Box 1 of 2), 1954-1956 (Offsite-box 34)
  Convent Cenacle, Mount Kisco, NY, 1954; NYC Transit Authority, 74th St. Power plant, 1955; Phelps Memorial Hospital, Mt. Pleasant, NY 1954; Power House, Grahamsville, NY, 1954; New York State Thruway, South Schenectady and Pattersonville, 1954; Gymnasium, Irvington, NJ, 1954; West Side Airlines Terminal, 42nd St., NYC, 1954; Junior High School 217, Queens, NY, 1954; Sutton View Apartments, 52nd St., NYC, 1955; Standard Vacuum Oil Co. Office Building, Harrison, NY, 1955; U.S. Gypsum Co., Stony Point, NY, 1955; Schering Corportation, Bloomfield, NJ, 1955; 425 Park Ave., NYC, 1955; Sewage Treatment Plant, Middletown, NY, 1956
- Files designated with a "H" (Box 2 of 2), 1956-1957 (Offsite-box 24)
  Roosevelt Raceway, Westbury, NY, 1956-1957 (13 folders); Merck and Co., Rahway, NJ, 1957
- Files designated with a "I", 1956-1958 (Offsite-box 47)
  Roosevelt Raceway/Racetrack, various buildings, Westbury, NY, 1956-1957 (9 folders); Allied Railing (Roosevelt Raceway), 1956; Kenneth Hargraves and Co., (Roosevelt Raceway), 1957; Lockwaood, Kessler and Bartlett (Raceway), 1957; Klemp Metal Grating Corp., (Raceway), 1957; Ruben and Malden Restaurant and Gas Station, NYS Thruway, 1956; Crew Quarters, 240th St., NYC, 1956; Garden State Plaza, 1956; 111-113 East 38th St., NYC, 1956; 74th St., Power plant, NYC Transit System, 1958
- Files designated with a "J" (Box 1 of 2), 1957-1959 (Offsite-box 20)
  Andrus Pavilion, Yonkers, NY, 1959; 165 East 66th St., NYC, 1956; Harlem Hospital, West 136th St., NYC, 1957; Lighthouse Queens Center, Woodhaven Boulevard, Rego Park, NY, 1957; Chase Manhattan Bank, 189 Broadway, 1957; 165 East 66th St., NYC, 1957; Warner-Chilcott Labs, Morris Plains, NJ 1958; Vassar Brothers Hospital, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1958; Caspary Research Building, East 71st St., NYC, 1958; Playbill Restaurant, Eighth Ave., NYC, 1958; Astor Hotel, Broadway at 44th Street, NYC, 1958; C.M.E. Office, (Chief Medical Examiner ), East 30th St., 1960; Broadway Savings Bank, Park Pl., 1959; Pepsi-Cola, Park Ave., 1958; New York Savings Bank, East 46th St., NYC, 1958; Union Carbide Labs, Eastview, NY, 1959; Hangar 15, Swiss Air Transport, New York International Airport (JFK), 1959;Manhattan Ear, Eye and Throat Hospital, East 64th St., NYC, 1959
- Files designated with a "J" (Box 2 of 2), 1958-1959 (Offsite-box 51)
  Monticello Raceway, Monticello, NY, 1958 (2 folders); Furnace Shrine, Sterling Forest, NY, 1959; Inwood Terrace Apartments, St. Nicholas Ave., NYC, 1959; Graymoor Seminary, Garrison, NY, 1959; Laundry for City Hospital, Kingston Ave. and Winthrop St., Brooklyn, NY, 1959; Lafayette National Bank, Brooklyn, NY, 1959; Gimbels Department Store, Roosevelt Field, NY, 1958; Loyola Hall, Fordham University, Bronx, NY, 1959; Speed Park Garage, 42nd St., NYC, 1959; B.O.A.C. (British Overseas Airway Corporation) Building, Idlewild, NY, 1959; Ivy Room, Drake Hotel, 56th St., NYC, 1959
- Files designated with a "K", 1960-1962 (Offsite-box 19)
  Morgan Library, East 36th St., NYC, 1960; Warner Chilcott Biochem Labs, Morris Plains, NJ, 1960; Bronx State Hospital, Building 102, 1960; C.W. Post College, Brookville, NY, Dorm #3, 1960; East River Station, Consolidated Edison (Con Ed), (Grand Iron Works, 525 Tiffany St., NYC), 1961; Guardian Life Insurance Annex Building, 50 Union Square, 1961; St. Joseph Cathedral, Hartford, CT, 1960; Nurses Residence, East 67th St., NYC, 1961; Inwood Heights Apartments, St. Nicholas Ave., NYC, 160; Port Authority Bus Terminal, 1961; 2 Columbus Circle, NYC, Broadway at 58th St., 1961; 555 Madison Ave., 1960; Stevens Institute, Hoboken, NJ, 1962
- Files designated with a "L" (Box 1 of 2), 1961 (Offsite-box 54)
  B.O.A.C. (British Overseas Airway Corporation), Idlewild, NY, 1961; Gimbels Department Store. Roosevelt Field, NY, 1961; Port Authority Bus Terminal, NYC, 1961 (3 folders); 30 East 65th St., NYC, 1961; Bronx Park East Apartments, Bronx, NY, 1961; Connecticut Bank and Trust Co., Hartford, CT, 1961; Episcopal Church Center, 815 Second Ave., NYC 1961; Public School 84, 91st St., NYC, 1961
- Files designated with a "L" (Box 2 of 2), 1962 (Offsite-box 12)
  330 Madison Ave., 1962 (2 folders); Yale Library, 1962; St. Vincent's Hospital, 1962; Endo Labs, Garden City, 1962
- Files designated with a "M" (Box 1 of 2), 1962-1963 (Offsite-box 17)
  Orbachs Department Store, Westbury, NY, 1962; 920 Park Ave., NYC, 1962; Republic Aviation, Farmingdale, NY, 1963; 650 Park Ave., 1962; St. Annes Church, Garden City, NY 1963; Schering Corporation, Bloomfield, NJ, 1963; First National City Bank, 399 Park Ave., NYC, 1963; World's Fair, Brass Rail, 1963
- Files designated with a "M" (Box 2 of 2), 1964 (Offsite-box 39)
  United Airlines, LaGuardia Airport, NYC, 1964; A.M.F. (American Machine and Foundry) Pavilion and Monorail, World's Fair, NYC, 1964; Brighton Beach Subway Station (B.M.T), Brooklyn, NY, 1964; Booth House, 15th St., NYC, 1964; Lady of the Sky, JFK Airport, 1964; R. Bisceglia Residence, Harrison, NY 1964
- Files designated with a "N" (Box 1 of 2), 1963 (Offsite-box 53)
  World's Fair, Queens, NY, 1963 (5 folders): Heliport, Chrysler, U.S. Pavilion (Bilco Co., West Haven, CT); Traveler's Insurance Co., Hartford, CT, 1963; Dealy Hall, Fordham University, 1963; Fortunoff's, Roosevelt Field, Westbury, NY, 1963
- Files designated with a "N" (Box 2 of 2), 1964-1965 (Offsite-box 13)
  The Lighthouse, East 59th St., NYC, 1963; Banco Popular, Puerto Rico, 1964; Syosset Community Park, 1964; Empire Trust Co., West 51st St., NYC, 1964; Incinerator, Bethpage, NY, 1964; Chrysler Building, Manufacturer Hanover Trust, 1965; A and S (Abraham and Straus) Annex, Livingston St. Brooklyn, NY, 1965; Russ Togs Warehouse, 27th St., Long Island City, NY. 1965; Huber Corporation, Edison Township, NJ, 1965; Metromedia, Inc., East 67th St., 1965
- Files designated with a "O", 1965-1966 (Offsite-box 30)
  Pan American Cargo Terminal, JFK Airport, 1965 (2 folders); 32 Avenue of the Americas (Sixth Ave.), 1966 (2 folders, including Antenna Tower); Convent Ave. Telephone Building, NYC, 1966; 140 West St., Telephone Building, NYC, 1966; Hoe Ave., Telephone Building, Bronx, NY (also Queens College and Convent Ave.), Queens College, 1966 (2 folders); Marine Midland Trust, Park Ave., 1966; Carlton Regency, 36th St., NYC, 1966; Loeb Building at Montefiore, 1965 (2 folders); Rainbow Grille at Rockefeller Center, 1966
- Files designated with a "P" (Box 1 of 2), 1944-1968 (Offsite-box 44)
  483 Greenwich St., NYC, 1944, and Linde Air Products Co., Hillside, NJ, 1944; War Shipping Administration, 44th St., 1944, and Fordham University, Broadway, NYC, 1944; Naval Powder Factory, Indian Head, MD, 1944; Biltmore Towers, White Plains, NY 1966; Lord and Taylor, Manhasset, NY, 1967; Travelers Data Center, Hartford, CT, 1968; Mother Cabrini Hospital, Edgecomb Ave., NYC, 1967; Bayview Rehabilitation Center, Eleventh Ave., NYC, 1967; Arlington Junior High School, La Grange, NY, 1966; Vanderbilt Replacement, St. Luke's Hospital, NYC, 1966; Administration Building, S.U.N.Y Stony Brook, NY, 1969; Suffolk State School, Building #80, 1967; 330 Madison Ave., NYC, 1966; Associated Dry Goods, Fifth Ave., 1966
- Files designated with a "P" (Box 2 of 2), 1966-1968 (Offsite-box 37)
  Mary Manning Walsh Home, York Ave., NYC, 1967; Metro-Media, 67th St., NYC, 1967; International Business Machines (I.B.M.) Seminar, 34th St., NYC, 1967; Long Beach Bridge, East Pine St., 1967; Lexington Ave., 77th St., Subway Station (I.R.T), 1968; Institute of Ophthalmology, 168th St., NYC, 1967; Suffolk State School, Melville, NY, 1966; Philharmonic Hall, Lincoln Center, 1969; Time Life, Inc., Sixth Ave., 1968; Marriott Hot Shoppes, JFK Airport, 1968; D. Williams Home, Sniffen Court, NY, 1966; Tuy Hoa Airbase, Republic of Vietnam, 1966; National Airlines Terminal, JFK, 1967; Jackson, Nash and Brophy, Madison Ave., NYC, 1965; Metropolitan Opera, NYC, 1967; Chelsea National Bank, 53rd St., NYC, 1967; Federal Reserve Bank, NYC, 1967; Catholic Home for the Blind, 71st St., NYC, 1968; Foster and Kleiser, Maspeth Ave., Maspeth, NY, 1968; "Miscellaneous" (all circa 1960s): Republic Steel Corp.; American Sugar; Caribe Hilton Hotel, Puerto Rico; Cantiague Park, Hicksville, NY; 20 State St., Boston, MA; 50 Rockefeller Center, NYC
- Files designated with a "Q" (Box 1 of 2), 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 5)
  Geigy Chemical Corp., Medical Lab, Ardsley, NY, 1968; Linde Consolidated Labs, Tarrytown NY, 1968; Greenacre Park, East 51st St., NYC, 1970; Lord and Taylor, Stamford CT, 1968; Pan American V.T.B., JFK Airport, 1968; Junior High School 72, 139th Ave., Queens, NY, 1965; Vassar Bros. Hospital, Poughkeepsie, NY, 1968; American Stock Exchange, Trinity Pl., NYC, 1968
- Files designated with a "Q" (2 of 2), 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 16)
  New York University Medical Center, East 33rd St., NYC, 1966; Hazeltine Corporation, Greenlawn, NY, 1970; BOCES (Board of Cooperative Educational Services) Dormitory #3, Deer Park, NY, 1972; Brookdale Hospital, Brooklyn, NY; 1968 (2 Folders); Bellevue Hospital, NYC; 1973; Hospital for Special Surgery, East 70th St., NYC, 1968; Franklin National Bank, Park Ave., NYC, 1970; Rockefeller University, East 64th St., 1970; First National Bank of Boston, 1969; Federal Reserve Bank, NYC; 1969-1970 (2 folders); Rockefeller Center (Western Union, RCA, Chase Bank), NYC, 1970; Chase Manhattan Bank, RCA Building, Rockefeller Center, 1969; British Petroleum, Fifth Ave., 1970
- Files designated with a "R" (Box 1 of 2), 1970-1975 (Offsite-box 41)
  Roosevelt Field Alexander's, 1970; I.B.M., M.I.S Computer Building, Sterling Forest, NY, 1970; North Central Bronx Hospital, East 210th St., Bronx, NY, 1971-1975 (2 folders); Stony Brook University, Humanities Library, 1970 (2 folders); Service Building Orange and Rockland County Utility, NY, 1970
- Files designated with a "R" (Box 2 of 2), 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 55)
  Geico Building, Woodbury Rd., Oyster Bay (folder marked Syosset), 1971; Sunrise Mall, Massapequa, NY, 1972; Newspoint, East River and Newtown Creek, Long Island City, NY, 1971 (5 folders)
- Files designated with a "S", 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 33)
  Primary [Public] School 198, Bronx, NY (DeVoe Iron Works), 1972; Telephone Company, East 79th St., NYC, 1972 (2 folders); I.B.M., Mt. Pleasant, NY (2 folders); H.I.P. Hospital, 102nd St., Forest Hills, NY, 1973; Federal Reserve Bank, 1973; 1 Beacon St., Boston, MA, 1973
- Files designated with a "T" (Box 1 of 2), 1969-1975 (Offsite-box 6)
  World Trade Center, Tower "A," 1969-1972 (8 folders); World Trade Center, Observation Deck, Tower "B," 1975
- Files designated with a "T" (Box 2 of 2), 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 52)
  8 folders: all World Trade Center, 1969-1973, including the Cortlandt Subway Station (I.R.T.)
- Files designated with a "U" (Box 1 of 2), 1968-1973 (Offsite-box 7)
  World Trade Center, Tower "B," 1968-1969 (2 folders); World Trade Center, Subgrade "Misc. sketches," 1969-1973; World Trade Center, Subgrade 1969-1973 (4 folders)
- Files designated with a "U" (Box 2 of 2), 1969-1973 (Offsite-box 42)
  7 folders: all World Trade Center, 1969-1973, including Northeast Plaza (5 World Trade Center), and Custom House (6 World Trade Center)
- Files designated with a "V", 1978-1983 (Offsite-box 45)
  "Miscellaneous" (2 folders, all circa 1980s NOTE: some projects appear in both folders): Mobil Corporation and Executive Dining Room, 42nd St., NYC; Tremaine Construction, 540 Madison Ave.; Westgate Apartments; 55 Broad St.; Stevens Institute; 275 Madison Ave.; Federated Department Store, 1440 Broadway, NYC; United Cerebral Palsy, Rye Brook, NY; Laidlaw, Adams and Peck, Madison Ave., NYC; North Central Bronx Hospital; Milliken; Cerny Residence, Bridgeville, PA; Saverio Crea Residence, Hillsdale, NJ; 810 Seventh Ave.; Manufacturers, New Rochelle, NY; James McKee Residence, Northport, NY; Hospital of Special Surgery, 70th St., NYC; 845 Third Ave.; 61 Madison Ave.; 365 Park Ave.; Hutton, Whitehall St., NYC; U.S. Trust Co., 54th St., NYC; 45 Broadway, NYC; 1 Thomson Pl., Long Island City, NY; Gurdjieff Foundation, 63rd St.; Leff Residence, Chappaqua, NYC; American Telephone, Plainview and Shirley; Schuster Residence; Public School 86, Queens, NY; Metromedia, 67th St., NYC; 810 Seventh Ave., NYC; Manufacturers Hanover Trust, New Rochelle, NY; WNET – 13; Walter Pestrock; New York University Fraternity House; New York Telephone Co., Staten Island, NY; Hotel Jordan, Aman, Jordan; Providence Rest Home; U.N German Mission, 65th St., NYC; John Lowry, Jr.; Misericordia Hospital, 233rd St; Bus Terminal; Lilco Wastewater, Northport, NY; World Trade Center, Tower A, 1978; London Terrace, 23rd St., NYC; United Airlines; American Airlines; Pan Am Worldport; Mercer Office, Sixth Ave., NYC; Cabrinit Hospital; General Motors Assembly Plant, Linden, NJ; Englert Residence, Mamaroneck, NY; Mt. Sinai Hospital; Rockefeller Center, Building 2, NYC; New Court Facility, Indiana Ave., NW, Washington, DC; Courthouse, Atlanta, GA; Neilson Residence, Bedford, NY; Intermediate School 227, Queens, NY
  Metromedia, "Phase Two and Three" 67th St., NYC, 1983 (5 folders)
- Files designated with a "W", 1974-1982 (Offsite-box 11)
  School of Dance, SUNY Purchase, Purchase, NY, 1974; Chemico Africa, 1974; Proskauer, 300 Park Ave., NY, 1976; Seaport Park, 117 Beekman St., NY, 1982
- Files designated with a "W", and with an "X" (Box 1 of 2), 1974-1981 (Offsite-box 10)
  St. Vincents Medical Center, Bard Ave., Staten Island, 1977; Federal Reserve Bank, 59 Maiden Lane, 1976-1980 (5 folders); Lighthouse, Elmhurst, NY, 1973; General Reinsurance, Greenwich, CT, 1974 (3 folders); A and S Store (Abraham and Straus), Huntington, NY, 1974; Hillcrest Archives, Pocantico Hills, NY, 1974; F.A.O. Schwarz, Fifth Ave., 1981
- Files designated with a "X" (Box 2 of 2), 1974-1979 (Offsite-box 9)
  ATT (AT and T) Long Lines, Rego Park, NY, 1974-1975 (2 folders); Stevens Institute (Morton), Hoboken, NJ 1975; Lutheran Medical Center, Brooklyn, 1976 (3 folders); Tropical Asia (Bronx Zoo), 1976; ATT 323 Broadway, NYC, 1976; Public School 380, Brooklyn, 1974; United States Trust, West 54th St., 1981; Greenpoint Bank, 32nd St., Astoria, NY, 1979; St. Vincents, Bard Ave., Staten Island, 1977
- Files designated with a "Y", 1960-1981, bulk 1970s (Offsite-box 29)
  Sears, Huntington, NY, 1979; Millstein Residence, 81st St., NYC, 1976; St. Vincent's Hospital, Seventh Ave., NYC, 1979; Doubleday, Fifth Ave., NYC, 1978; Life Sciences Building, Columbia University, 1981; W.N.E.T., Channel 13, 57th St., NYC, 1977 (3 folders); Tiffany, 57th St., 1979 (2 folders); "Miscellaneous" (2 folders): all circa 1960s: General Motors, National Geographic, Washington, DC; Fordham University; I.B.M.; Roosevelt Field Shopping Center; NYS Exhibition, World's Fair; Flushing Meadow Stadium; Noxema; American Bible Society; Hartford National Bank; Pfizer; Brooklyn Aquarium at Coney Island; Federal Reserve Bank; Middlesex Hospital; University Club; various residences; Caribe Hilton Hotel; Triboro Bridge; National Airlines at Rockefeller Center; R.C.A.
- Files designated with a "Z", 1977-1982 (Offsite-box 35)